Finding Aid to the Margaret Sanger papers SSC.MS.00138
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES, 1903-1966
  - Planned Parenthood Federation of America
    - Publications
      - Lists, 1951-62 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Press releases, 1941-61 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Reports
      - General, 1942-62 (Box 45, Folder 6)
      - Financial reports and budgets, 1942-62 (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Clinics, 1943-48 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Memoranda and notes to affiliates, 1942-62 (Box 46, Folder 3-4)
    - Form letters, 1942-60 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Lists of offices/staff, 1942-62 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Standards of affiliation, 1943-62 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Nominating committee (proposed nominations), 1953-61 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Addresses and speeches, 1947-64 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Conference and event programs, invitations, agendas, and seating lists, 1943-62 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - World Population Emergency Campaign
    - General, 1960 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1960-62 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Minutes, 1960-61 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Organizational memos, 1960-62 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Publications
      - General, 1960-64 (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - News of Population and Birth Control, 1960-61 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Reports
      - General, 1958-61 (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - Travel reports on Asia by George and Barbara Cadbury, 1960-61 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - A - L
    - American Civil Liberties Union, 1933-47 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - The American Eugenics Society, Inc., 1930-57 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - American Fund for Public Service, 1926-31 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - American Genetic Association, undated (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - American Humanist Association, 1960-61 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - American Institute of Family Relations, 1938-44 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - American Medical Association, 1933-38 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - American Neurological Association, 1937; 1938 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - American Nurses Association, 1936-37 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - American Woman's Association, 1939 (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - Association for Voluntary Sterilization, Inc., 1968 (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - Committee of One Hundred, 1917 (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - Eugenics Society, 1930-56 (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - Fertility Research Institute, 1954 (Box 48, Folder 14)
    - Freethinkers of America, 1941 (Box 48, Folder 15)
    - Human Betterment Association, 1952-60 (Box 48, Folder 16)
    - Institute of Feminine Hygiene, 1932 (Box 48, Folder 17)
    - International Medical Group for the Investigation of Contraception, 1929-34 (Box 48, Folder 18)
    - International Neo-Malthusian Bureau of Correspondence and Defence, 1915 (Box 48, Folder 19)
    - International Union for the Scientific Investigation of Population Problems, 1931 (Box 48, Folder 20)
    - League of Nations, 1923-26 (Box 48, Folder 21)
  - M - Z
    - Malthusian League, 1908-56 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Maternity Center Association, 1929 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Methodist Overseas Relief Committee, undated; 1948; 1951 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - National Birth Control League, 1916-18 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - National Committee on Maternal Health, 1928-34 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - National Resources Planning Board, 1940; 1941 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - New York City Department of Health, 1940-49 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Population Control, 1955-60 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Population Reference Bureau
      - General, 1933-62 (Box 49, Folder 9)
      - Press releases, 1958-62 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - United Nations - World Health Organization, 1952 (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - United World Federalists, Inc., 1942-48 (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - Voluntary Parenthood League, 1919-25; undated (Box 49, Folder 13-13a)
    - Women's City Club of New York, 1941 (Box 49, Folder 14)
    - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom, 1934 (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Foundations
    - Brush, 1944-59 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Doris Duke, 1937-55 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Milbank Memorial Fund, 1936-50 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Watumull, 1947-64 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - William C. Whitney, 1940; 1941 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Conferences
    - Historical outline of birth control conferences, undated (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Population Problem Conference, Paris, 1903-1904 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Birth Control Mass Meeting, Rochester, NY, 1917 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Eastern States Conference on Birth Control, New York City, 1918 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - American Birth Control Conference, 1st, New York City, 1921 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - International Birth Control Conference, Fifth, 1922 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Middle Western States Birth Control Conference, Chicago, 1923 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Neo-Malthusian and Birth Control Conference, 6th, New York, 1925 (Box 51, Folder 8-9)
    - Southern California Conference on Modern Parenthood, Los Angeles, 1926 (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - Institute of Politics Conference, Williamstown, MA, 1926 (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - World Population Conference, Geneva, 1927
      - Programs, announcements, press releases, and invitations (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Menu (with cartoon "Vive le Bebe") (Box 52, Folder 2)
        See Flat File
      - Address book (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - Publications
        - Journal and miscellaneous (Box 52, Folder 4)
        - Proceedings (Box 52)
      - Photographs (Box 52, Folder 5)
      - Scrapbook (Box 52, Folder 6)
      - Speeches (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - International Conference of Social Work, Paris, 1928 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - World League for Sexual Reform, World Congress, Copenhagen, 1928 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Western States Conference on Birth Control and Population Problems, Los Angeles, 1930 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - International Congress for Sex Research, 2nd, London, 1930 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - International Birth Control Conference, 7th, Zurich, 1930
      - Programs (Box 53, Folder 5)
      - List of members (Box 53, Folder 6)
      - Accounts (Box 53, Folder 7)
      - Papers (Box 53, Folder 8)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Conference on Birth Control in Asia, London, 1933 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - American Conference on Birth Control and National Recovery, Washington, DC, 1934 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - International Congress for Sex Reform, 5th, 1934 (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - Conference on Contraceptive Research and Clinical Practice, New York, 1936 (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - Regional Conference of Western States on Birth Control (proposed), Los Angeles, 1937 (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - Southern Conference on Tomorrow's Children, Atlanta, 1941 (Box 53, Folder 15)
    - International Congress on Population and World Resources, Cheltenham, England, 1948 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - World Movement for World Federal Government, Luxembourg Congress, 1948 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - International Conference on Planned Parenthood, 3rd, Bombay, 1952
      - Programs and agenda items (Box 54, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence (Box 54, Folder 4)
      - Sponsors and contributors (Box 54, Folder 5)
      - Press releases (Box 54, Folder 6)
      - Resolutions, reports, and background material (Box 54, Folder 7)
      - Papers (Box 54, Folder 8)
      - Proceedings (Box 54, Folder 9)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - International Conference on Planned Parenthood, 4th, 1953 (Box 55, Folder 1-3)
    - International Planned Parenthood Federation Western Hemisphere Region Conference on Population Problems and Family Planning, San Juan, 1955 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - International Conference on Planned Parenthood, 5th, Tokyo, 1955
      - Correspondence (Box 55, Folder 5)
      - Programs (Box 55, Folder 6)
      - Sponsors and contributions (Box 55, Folder 7)
      - Invitations (Box 55, Folder 8)
      - Speeches (Box 55, Folder 9)
      - Photographs (Box 55, Folder 10)
      - Clippings (Box 55, Folder 11)
      - Proceedings (Box 55, Folder 12)
      - Papers and miscellaneous (Box 56, Folder 1-3)
    - International Conference on Planned Parenthood, 6th (proposed), Washington, DC, 1957 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - International Conference on Planned Parenthood, 6th, New Delhi, 1959
      - Correspondence (Box 56, Folder 5)
      - Programs (Box 56, Folder 6)
      - Reports and resolutions (Box 56, Folder 7)
      - Proceedings (Box 56, Folder 8)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - A New Look at the Population Crisis Conference, Dallas, 1960 (Box 56, Folder 10)
- SERIES V. COUNTRIES AND REGIONS, 1885-1983
  Series V. is arranged alphabetically by country and by state. Each file is also arranged by document types (correspondence, reports, printed material, clippings).
  This series contains alphabetical files on birth control activities in many U.S. states, and countries from all five continents. Clippings and printed material are most prevalent. Correspondence and reports are also included. Separate boxes contain substantial documentation on birth control activities in Japan and India, countries which became the focus of the international movement, as well as England, France, and Germany.
  The general countries files contain considerable material on Asian and Latin American countries. Most of the documentation dates from the 1950s and is linked to IPPF activities, although there are some records and publications that Sanger collected on her various world tours in the 1920s and 1930s.
  The large file on England consists of extensive publications from the late 19th century to the 1950s, including early pamphlets on population control and contraception, and writings of Marie Stopes; information on several clinics and birth control organizations, including the Family Planning Association, National Birth Control Association, and Walworth Women's Welfare Centre; and numerous news extracts, articles and reprints.
  Files on France and Germany contain many early and significant publications on Malthusian doctrine, sexual hygiene, contraception, and fertility studies.
  The box on India includes many publications put out by the Family Planning Association of India, information on conferences, reports chronicling initial efforts to organize birth control activities in India, and a small amount of correspondence largely related to IPPF matters. The files also contain several government publications and numerous clippings.
  The boxes on Japan contain a small amount of correspondence, some of which relates to General Douglas MacArthur's decision to deny Sanger a visa to enter Japan in 1950; reports; and a file on Japan birth control organizations which include important historical information on the history of the movement in Japan and the issue of population growth. The material on Japan also includes a large clipping file mostly covering the 1950s, and many publications printed in Japanese.
  The states files cover 37 states and date mostly from the late 1930s to the 1950s. The Arizona file contains photographs of Mexican-American families for a case history study conducted by the Tucson Mother's Clinic.
  - Arabia, 1931(?) (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Argentina, 1935 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Australia, 1936-54 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Austria, 1951-57 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Belgium, 1955-59 (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Bermuda, 1951; 1958 (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Brazil, 1940 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - British West Indies, 1951; 1954 (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Burma, 1937-61 (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Canada, 1935-63 (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Ceylon, 1951-59 (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - China, 1933-65 (Box 57, Folder 12-15)
  - Cuba, 1938-44 (Box 57, Folder 16)
  - Denmark, 1928-64 (Box 57, Folder 17)
  - Egypt, 1937; 1969 (Box 57, Folder 18)
  - Europe, 1931-51 (Box 57, Folder 19)
  - Finland, 1940; 1949 (Box 57, Folder 20)
  - Guatemala, 1934 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Haiti, 1932 (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Hong Kong, 1951-61 (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Iceland, 1937 (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Indo-China, 1939; undated (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Indonesia, 1951-59 (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Israel, 1938-55 (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Italy, 1926-62 (Box 58, Folder 8-9)
  - Jamaica, 1939-70 (Box 58, Folder 10)
  - Korea, 1954 (Box 58, Folder 11)
  - Lithuania, 1929-33 (Box 58, Folder 12)
  - Malaya, 1958; undated (Box 58, Folder 13)
  - Mexico, 1932-61 (Box 58, Folder 14)
  - Natal, 1960-61 (Box 58, Folder 15)
  - Nepal, 1959 (Box 58, Folder 16)
  - Netherlands, 1924-39 (Box 58, Folder 17)
  - New Zealand, 1937-60 (Box 58, Folder 18)
  - Norway, 1936 (Box 58, Folder 19)
  - Pakistan, 1957-58 (Box 58, Folder 20)
  - Philippines, 1936-60 (Box 58, Folder 21)
  - Poland, 1962 (Box 58, Folder 22)
  - Puerto Rico, 1932-62 (Box 58, Folder 23)
  - Singapore, 1951-61 (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - South Africa, 1938-53 (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Southern Rhodesia, 1960 (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - Spain, 1921-52 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Sweden, 1924-57 (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Switzerland, 1930-50 (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Thailand, 1959-67 (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - Tonga, 1950-51 (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - Trinidad and Tobago, 1937-64 (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - Union of South Africa, 1949; 1953 (Box 59, Folder 10)
  - USSR, 1933-56 (Box 59, Folder 11-12)
  - Venezuela, 1964 (Box 59, Folder 13)
  - Yugoslavia, 1954 (Box 59, Folder 14)
  - England
    - General, 1934-36 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Reports, 1942-55 (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Marie Stopes: Pamphlets and clippings, 1922-62 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Family Planning Association
      - General, 1947-59 (Box 60, Folder 4)
      - Annual reports, 1941-59 (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Iona Education Centre, 1955-60 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Manchester, Salford, and District Mother's Clinic for Birth Control, undated (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - National Birth Control Association, 1932-38 (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - North Kensington Marriage Welfare Centre, 1953; undated (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - Sex Education Centre, undated (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - Walworth Women's Welfare Centre, 1925-34 (Box 60, Folder 11)
    - Worker's Birth Control Group, undated (Box 60, Folder 12)
    - Publications
      - News extracts (typescripts), 1937-58 (Box 60, Folder 13)
      - Articles, 1933-51 (Box 60, Folder 14)
      - Reprints, 1911-59 (Box 60, Folder 15)
      - Pamphlets, nineteenth century (Box 61, Folder 1)
      - Pamphlets, 1904-50 (Box 61, Folder 2-3)
  - France
    - General, 1957-58 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1954-58 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Clippings, 1955-61 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Publications, 1897-1956; undated (Box 62, Folder 4-7)
  - Germany
    - General, 1930-60 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1949; 1956; undated (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Reports, 1931-55 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Articles and Periodicals, 1929-59 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Clippings, 1940-61 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Pamphlets, 1885-1932 (Box 64)
  - India
    - General, 1930-61 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1951-57 (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Reports, 1936-58 (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Family Planning Association of India, 1951; 1955 (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Invitations, 1951-59 (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Publications
      - Newsletters and bulletins, 1933-67 (Box 65, Folder 6)
      - Articles, 1928-55 (Box 65, Folder 7)
      - Reprints, 1933-61 (Box 65, Folder 8)
      - Journals, 1948-61 (Box 65, Folder 9)
      - Clippings, 1935-58 (Box 65, Folder 10)
      - Pamphlets, 1929-60 (Box 66, Folder 1)
      - Conference reports and proceedings, 1951-59 (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Japan
    - Correspondence, 1937-54 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Minutes, reports of meetings, and conferences, 1949-54 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Reports
      - General, 1930-54 (Box 67, Folder 3)
      - Statistical reports, petitions (?) in Japanese text, undated (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Birth control organizations, 1951-56 (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - M. Sanger's 1954 trip: Speeches, reports, and newsletter (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - Invitations, cards, addresses, 1954-59 (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - "History of Planned Parenthood Movement in Japan" by Johnson Kung-ti Shing, 1957 (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - Clippings
      - General, 1936-55 (Box 67, Folder 9-10)
      - Mainichi newspapers, 1952; 1965 (Box 67, Folder 11)
    - Photographs, 1947; 1948; undated (Box 67, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous, 1934-59 (Box 67, Folder 13)
    - Publications
      - Articles, 1936-59 (Box 68, Folder 1)
      - Toyohiko Kagawa: Biographical material, 1936; 1937; undated (Box 68, Folder 2)
      - Pamphlets, 1932-61 (Box 68, Folder 3)
      - "An Outline of the Institute of Population Problems", undated (Box 69, Folder 4)
      - The World of Obstetrics and Gynecology (commemorative issue), 1955 (Box 69, Folder 5)
      - Publications in Japanese, undated (Box 69, Folder 1-4)
      - Omei Illustrated Guide Book, by Huang Shou-fu and T'an Chung-yo, with an English translation, 1936 (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - United States
    - Alabama, 1938-41 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Arizona, 1935-58 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Arkansas, 1938; 1954 (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - California, 1930-54 (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Colorado, 1951 (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Connecticut, 1937-83 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Delaware, 1934-38 (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - Florida, 1937-38 (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - Georgia, 1939; 1940 (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - Hawaii, 1936-37 (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - Idaho, 1935 (Box 71, Folder 11)
    - Illinois, 1917-56 (Box 71, Folder 12)
    - Indiana, 1936-51 (Box 71, Folder 13)
    - Iowa, 1938 (Box 71, Folder 14)
    - Kentucky, 1936-38 (Box 71, Folder 15)
    - Maine, 1937-38 (Box 71, Folder 16)
    - Maryland, 1929; 1931; 1979 (Box 71, Folder 17)
    - Massachusetts, 1930-48 (Box 71, Folder 18-19)
    - Michigan, 1931-39 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Minnesota, 1937-38 (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Missouri, 1937-60 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - New Hampshire, 1938-39 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - New Jersey, 1929-43 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - New Mexico, 1937 (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - New York, 1936-62 (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - North Carolina, 1938-41 (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - Ohio, 1930-57 (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - Oklahoma, 1936-38 (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - Oregon, undated (Box 72, Folder 11)
    - Pennsylvania, 1931-38 (Box 72, Folder 12)
    - Rhode Island, 1937-39 (Box 72, Folder 13)
    - Tennessee, 1937-39 (Box 72, Folder 14)
    - Texas, 1937-58 (Box 72, Folder 15)
    - Vermont, 1937-38 (Box 72, Folder 16)
    - Virginia, 1935-39 (Box 72, Folder 17)
    - Washington DC, 1937-58 (Box 72, Folder 18)
    - West Virginia, 1938-39 (Box 72, Folder 19)
    - Wisconsin, 1938 (Box 72, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous clinics, 1932-38 (Box 72, Folder 21)
- SERIES VI. SUBJECT FILES, 1761-1969
  The subject files are arranged alphabetically by subject.
  They contain printed material, clippings, reports, and some correspondence regarding various topics related to birth control, population, sexuality, health, medicine, legal issues, and religion, among other topics. These files frequently duplicate printed material found in the SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES and SERIES V. COUNTRIES AND REGIONS. This series is an excellent source for historical material on the history of contraception and population control. It includes many late 19th century and early 20th century publications.
  The files on contraception and eugenics, along with a history file (containing mostly historical outlines and articles from the English publication, the Malthusian), a file on Malthus and Malthusianism, a large amount of material on Sex Education, including early pamphlets and publications from England, Sweden and the U.S., and the Legal files make up a core collection of historical materials on the roots of the American birth control movement.
  Of particular interest are the files on abortion, which include research, statistical information and some apocryphal stories on the illegal abortion industry, as well as some influential arguments in favor of legalizing abortion, such as A. J. Rongy's "Abortion and Birth Control."
  Along with the Records of the Margaret Sanger Research Bureau, a separate collection in the Sophia Smith Collection, the Contraception subject files provide one of the best sources of material on the history of contraceptive research and education. These files contain numerous 19th century publications for women, including catalogs of hygiene devices; popular marital guides from the 20th century; research publications on the use and effectiveness of specific contraceptive methods; and a large number of short guides written by physicians. Additional material on contraception is located throughout the subject files, particularly under Marriage, Medicine, Population, and Sex Education.
  Studies on eugenics and heredity can be located in separate files under Eugenics, Heredity and Mental Hygiene. These files contain many of the seminal works on eugenics written during the early part of the century that influenced the thinking of Sanger and other leaders in the birth control movement, including publications by Moses Harmon, C.V. Drysdale, and Raymond Pearl, as well as many pamphlets and propaganda materials put out by the American Eugenics Society and the Brush Foundation, and numerous scientific papers.
  Legal materials, filed under Laws, Legal Cases, and Legislation contain publications, briefs and other legal documents covering several significant cases, including the D. M. Bennett trial in 1879, the City of Portland vs. Emma Goldman and Ben Reitman in 1915, the arrest and trial of William Sanger in 1915, and the 1921 Town Hall Raid in New York. Also included are transcripts of laws and proposed laws, a list of birth control advocates who have received prison sentences, and published transcripts of Supreme Court and Congressional hearings on matters or cases related to birth control.
  The large Population files are composed of statistical studies and research reports, and cover many individual countries.
  - Abortion (Box 72)
    - General, 1920-64 (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Abortion Law Reform Association: Newsletters and publications, 1949; 1954 (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - Natalidad Mortalidad Maternidad y Aborto by Jose Chelala-Aguilera, 1937 (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - Adolescence, 1931-32 (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - Adoption, 1943-45 (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - Anti-birth control, 1917-37 (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - Artificial insemination, 1941-56 (Box 73, Folder 7)
  - Bibliographies, 1918-53 (Box 73, Folder 8)
  - Birth rate, 1905-50 (Box 73, Folder 9)
  - Censorship, 1903-39 (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - Child labor, 1940; 1944 (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - Child welfare, 1930; 1943 (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - Clinics, 1917-42 (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - Crime and criminals, 1936; 1941; undated (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - Contraception
    - General, 1917-50 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Techniques, 1761-1934 (Box 74, Folder 7-8)
    - Techniques, 1935-1950; undated (Box 75, Folder 1-2)
    - Catalogues, 1931; undated (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Reprints, 1928-60 (Box 75, Folder 4-5)
    - Clippings, 1938-69 (Box 75, Folder 6)
  - Delinquents, 1922-35 (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Disease, 1872-1956 (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - Economics, 1904-38; undated (Box 76, Folder 3-4)
  - Employment and unemployment, 1928-44 (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - Eugenics, 1905-50 (Box 76, Folder 6-7)
  - Euthanasia, 1939-61 (Box 76, Folder 8)
  - Family life, 1927-46 (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Family planning, 1941; 1949 (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Feminism, 1915; 1934 (?) (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Fertility, 1930-52 (Box 77, Folder 4-5)
  - Heredity, 1870-1943 (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - History, 1910-49 (Box 78, Folder 1-2)
  - Homosexuality, 1905; 1954 (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - Infant mortality, 1922; 1939; undated (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - Infertility, 1913-60 (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - Laws and criminal statutes on birth control, 1870-1935 (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - Legal cases
    - Miscellaneous, 1821-1940 (Box 79, Folder 2-4)
    - Brownsville clinic, 1917 (Box 79, Folder 5)